A Guide to the Papers of the Baylor Family, 1749-1920
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the Baylor Family 1749-1920
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
9732-c
ca. 611 items (1 box).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The collection was purchased by the Library from Jerry Showalter on January 10, 1973.
Scope and Content
Most of the items are promissory notes, receipts and accounts of George Baylor. Many concern the settlement of the estate of Jacob Baylor. The collection also contains a variety of court orders and summonses for Rockingham County, Va. There are a few items of correspondence in the 1890s, almost all concerning court and financial matters.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged chronologically.
Contents List
- Copies of Land Tract Deeds, Loan Agreement, Indenture between James Peary & John Achenbright, Letter cover, License for Marriage of Daughter by Sam Hunter, 1783 emanicipation document 1749-1793, 9 items
- Receipt for Taxes to George Bailer (Baylor), Receipt from Martin Baylor to James Alled 1779-1797, 2 items
- Estate Debts of Jacob Baylor & receipts to George Baylor and Jacob Baylor 1798, 5 items
- Receipt of sale of slave to George Baylor, receipt of payment to surveyor by George Baylor 1799, 2 items
- Copy of Definition of Land deeded by Harmon Lovingood to Adolph Spinole, Relinquish of Claim to slaves by Philip Gloninger 1799, 2 items
- Receipt to George Baylor, assignment of bill to George Baylor 1800, 2 items
- Manumission of a slave by Jacob Parrott 1801
- Survey tract & receipts to George Baylor, pledge for debt payment by (?) 1801-1802, 2 items
- Certification of age for marriage 1803
- Receipts, notes of various resident of Rockingham County 1803-1818, 15 items
- Claim to George Baylor as executor of Jacob Baylor's estate, note from G.H. Morn to George Baylor, tax receipt to George Baylor 1804, 3 items
- Receipt from John Harrison 1805 September
- Account of estate of Jacob Baylor, receipts to George Baylor 1805-1806, 5 items
- Receipts, memorandum for law suit for George Baylor 1807, 7 items
- Requests to the Jacob Baylor Estate 1808, 2 items
- Receipts to George Baylor, copy of court business re George Baylor 1809, 4 items
- Receipts to George Baylor, promissory note of George Baylor 1810, 8 items
- Memorandum in suit for payment of debt, petition for executors of estate, payment to John Knight for collection of debt 1808-1810, 3 items
- Promissory notes and receipts of George Baylor 1811, 8 items
- Receipts, promissory notes, & memoranda 1812-1815, 9 items
- Receipts to George Baylor 1813, 4 items
- Receipts to George Baylor 1814, 4 items
- Bill of Sale of slave to George Baylor, receipts to George Baylor, copy of Deed of Land sold to George Baylor 1815, 16 items
- Receipts to George Baylor 1816, 12 items
- Receipts to George Baylor 1817, 8 items
- Receipts & promissory notes to George Baylor 1818, 14 items
- Receipts to George Baylor 1819, 7 items
- Accounts, memoranda, depositions, & receipts 1818-1819, 17 items
- Receipts to George Baylor 1820-1821, 11 items
- Court suits 1821, 24 items
- Receipts of George Baylor 1822, 9 items
- Receipts of payments to Sheriff by George Baylor 1823, 13 items
- Accounts, receipts of George Baylor 1824, 12 items
- Receipts, accounts to George Baylor 1825, 12 items
- Receipts, promissory note to George Baylor 1826, 6 items
- Receipts to George Baylor 1827-1828, 10 items
- Receipts, accounts for George Baylor 1829, 14 items
- Receipts to George Baylor 1830, 6 items
- Receipts to George Baylor 1831, 11 items
- Receipts, accounts of the Burns family 1831-1838, 7 items
- Receipts, accounts, depositions to George Baylor 1832, 14 items
- Receipts, accounts to George Baylor 1833, 15 items
- Accounts, receipts to George Baylor 1834, 24 items
- Receipts, accounts 1835, 25 items
- Receipts, promissory notes for George Baylor 1836, 8 items
- Receipts, accounts to George Baylor 1837, 16 items
- Receipts, accounts, memoranda of George Baylor 1838, 20 items
- Receipts & accounts for court expenses of George Baylor 1839, 15 items
- Accounts, receipts for George Baylor 1840, 18 items
- Receipts, accounts for George Baylor 1841, 18 items
- Accounts, receipts, promissory notes of George Baylor 1842, 10 items
- Receipts, accounts of George & Jacob Baylor 1843, 9 items
- Receipts, accounts of the Baylor family 1844, 22 items
- Accounts, receipts of the Baylor family 1845, 16 items
- Accounts, receipts for the Baylor family 1846, 13 items
- Receipts of George Baylor 1847-1848, 4 items
- Receipts & inheritance claims of the Burns family 1850-1858, 6 items
- Receipts, Order of Auction for Collection of Debt 1860-1862, 4 items
- Complaints to the court, promissory notes 1865-1869, 6 items
- Complaints to the court, sworn statement for recovery of indebtedness 1870-1873, 9 items
- Receipt 1880
- Wm. M. McAllister to John Burns, Indenture & bid for work 1885-1886, 3 items
- Correspondence & papers of A.N. Burns 1892-1899, 10 items
- Postcards to A.N. Burns, receipt to A.G. Glick 1901-1920, 3 items
- Accounts, receipts, miscellaneous n.d., 24 items